Matthew Wade

Lakeland, Florida | 863-845-6350 | tylerwade124@gmail.com | GitHub | LinkedIn | Portfolio

Software Engineer

As a seasoned tradesman and experienced crew leader, I bring a unique blend of practical skills and technical expertise to my role as a software engineer. My dedication to continuous learning and problem-solving, combined with my ability to effectively collaborate with team members, allows me to deliver thoughtful solutions and valuable insights to any project. I am driven by my passion for using technology to create real-world impact.

SKILLS / TOOLS

- Programming Languages : JavaScript, Python, SQL
- Databases: PostgreSQL, Django, RESTful APIs
- Frameworks : React, Express, Sequelize, Node.js
- Version Control : Git
- Tools: VSCode, GitHub, Git, Insomnia, Postico, Zoom, Slack, Various Wireframing Programs

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Software Engineering Immersive | General Assembly | October 2022 - January 2023

Successfully completed 500+ hours of expert-led instruction in Front-End, Back-End, and Full-Stack Web Development and hands-on learning of teamwork, and software-engineering fundamentals and the industry's most in demand technologies. Developed projects, including:

- TypeThis | A typing game based off of multiple API calls to an API that hosts quotes with sub-topics. The user selects a topic, then begins a typing test and receives accurate calculations of WPM, accuracy, amount of errors, and time | Built with React, Javascript | Demo | GitHub
- Digital Classroom | A full stack, CRUD application created with a dev team of 2 other people.
 Created for instructors at General Assembly to keep track of students assignments within each
 cohort the instructor is teaching or has taught. A user(instructor) can create an account, create
 classes, create students, and add assignments to each of those students. | Built with React,
 Javascript | GitHub
- AllChat | A full stack, CRUD, real time chat application utilizing Django-channels and websockets where users can register/sign-in/logout and update their account, then chat with other users that have joined the chat room. | Built with Python, Django, Javascript, SQL, postgres, Django-channels, websockets | GitHub

Retail Sales Associate | Publix | Winter Haven, FL | June 2022 - Present

- Assist an average of 100 customers per day by finding or selecting items to fulfill their needs.
- Maintain strong relationships with customers, and keep products clean and orderly on the shelves.

Subcontractor | United Fabrication & Maintenance | Winter Haven, FL | March 2021 - December 2021

- Led a crew and carried out large and small scale maintenance tasks (electrical, plumbing, and painting) in distribution centers for companies such as Home Depot, and Pep Boys.
- Accurately estimated costs and timelines for major projects in distribution centers.
- Handled hundreds of large scale and small scale maintenance work orders with efficiency and attention to detail for companies such as Pep Boys and Home Depot.

Electrician | Heart of Florida Electric | Auburndale, FL | March 2020 - January 2021

- Installed and repaired electrical systems such as generators, fans, receptacles, and light fixtures in residential, and commercial environments.
- Solved complex electrical problems as part of the service crew.

EDUCATION

General Assembly | Software Engineering Immersive | January 2023